Guide to the Bacon Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Original accession, 1729-1936; Part I
  - Manuscripts, 1729-1881; Series III
    - Writings of others
      - Bisler, Mrs. Charles
        - "Soul of France Through Fifty Years of Peace & War", Undated (Box 14, Folder 68)
      - Hooker, T., copies of his letters (1640, 46-47) taken from the "Hutchinson Papers" by L. W. Bacon, Undated (Box 14, Folder 69)
      - Parks, Alice, "A Parting Scene" (poem), Undated (Box 14, Folder 70)
      - Peck, Alice B., last will and testament of, 1857 (Box 14, Folder 71)
      - Stiles, Ezra, diary, excerpts copied from, 1769-1779 (Box 14, Folder 72)
    - Anonymous or unidentified
      - "Anticipation and Memory," dispute at the Junior Exhibition, Yale College, 1819 (Box 14, Folder 73)
      - Bacon, Leonard, biographical sketch of, Undated (Box 14, Folder 74)
      - Bacon, Leonard, two memorial sermons on, 1882 (Box 14, Folder 75)
      - Bacon's circular, answers to inquiries in, Undated (Box 14, Folder 76)
      - Baptismal covenant, form of parents for children, 1856 (Box 14, Folder 77)
      - Beaumont, William, copy of epitaph for, 1881 (Box 14, Folder 78)
      - Bible class lessons, 1873-1881 (Box 14, Folder 79)
      - Industrial school society of New Haven, ladies committee minutes [at the end of the volume], 1856 (Box 14, Folder 79)
      - "Capt. Hall's Travels in the United States," book review, Undated (Box 14, Folder 80)
      - Church council organizing, lectures on, Undated (Box 14, Folder 81)
      - "College Life in 1820," correspondence for a biography of Leonard Bacon by a grandson, Undated (Box 14, Folder 82)
      - Confession of faith, critical notes on, Undated (Box 14, Folder 83)
      - "'Confessions of an Old Man' by the author of 'Scenes in Georgia', 'Christian Martyrs', etc.", Undated (Box 14, Folder 84)
        General note
        See also: folder 103.
      - "Constitutional Questions," answers to three, 1886 (Box 14, Folder 85)
      - Debates (at Yale Commencements) on various subjects: Italy, party spirit, causes of character, Indians, abilities of the sexes in comparison, 1820, undated (Box 15, Folder 86)
      - Diary of an unidentified person (L. W. Bacon?), 1824-1825 (Box 15, Folder 87)
      - "Dickens and Thackery", Undated (Box 15, Folder 88)
      - Hillhouse, James, memoranda concerning his funeral, 1833 (Box 15, Folder 89)
      - Horsemanship, and deer, notes on, Undated (Box 15, Folder 90)
      - Independent, The, editors resignation and explanation, Undated (Box 15, Folder 91)
      - "Inspiration," notes for an article, Undated (Box 15, Folder 92)
      - Installation of the clergy, an address for, 1848-1849 (Box 15, Folder 93)
      - "Is National Wealth Incompatible with National Virtue?", Undated (Box 15, Folder 94)
      - Journal, Undated (Box 15, Folder 95)
      - "Literature of the Puritan Age", Undated (Box 15, Folder 96)
      - "Municipal Government", Undated (Box 15, Folder 97)
      - [Offenbach's] new operetta--"The Elopement," libretto, Undated (Box 15, Folder 98)
      - Play, untitled and fragmentary, Undated (Box 15, Folder 99)
      - Poetry, miscellaneous, 1817, undated (Box 15, Folder 100)
      - "Presbyterianism in New England" and "Presbyterian Leaven and the Halfway Covenant", Undated (Box 15, Folder 101)
      - "Restoration of the Stuarts", Undated (Box 15, Folder 102)
      - "'Serious Hours, or Miscellaneous Religious Sketches,' by the author of 'Memoir of Eliza J. Drysdale', 'Christian Martyrs,' etc., Vol. 1", Undated (Box 15, Folder 103)
        See also: folder 84.
      - Sermons, Undated (Box 15, Folder 104)
      - Services schedule book, 1878-1879 (Box 15, Folder 105)
      - "Should Sara Bernhardt be Allowed to Perform?", outline, 1891 (Box 15, Folder 106)
      - Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 15, Folder 107-113)
  - Printed matter, 1812-1900; Series IV
    This series consists of newspaper clippings, magazine articles and pamphlets, and newsclipping scrapbooks. There is also one folder containing the "Protest of the Minority" in the McWhorter trial, 1847. Most of the newspaper clippings are taken from The Independent, a religious newspaper, and many deal with the problem of slavery in the United States. The magazine articles and pamphlets are mostly of a religious nature, and cover such topics as local church affairs, temperance societies, and foreign missions. Many of the newspaper articles and pamphlets were written by the Reverend Leonard Bacon. The folders are arranged chronologically by year, with a special folder at the end of each section for undated items. The scrapbooks reflect only a general grouping chronologically and by subject matter.
    - Newspaper clippings
      - 1829-1852 (Box 16, Folder 1-3)
      - Articles written by Leonard Bacon, 1852 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - 1853-1881 (Box 16, Folder 5-9)
      - includes poems, Undated (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - "Protest of the Minority"--the McWhorter trial, 1847 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Magazine articles and pamphlets, 1812-1899, undated (Box 17, Folder 12-14)
    - Newsclipping scrapbooks
      - Slavery and the Choctaw Indian missions, Bushnell, denominational subjects and church doctrines, 1848-1850 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Slavery and the Civil War, 1855-1865 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - L. W. Bacon's travels in the Near East; letters concerning the U.S. Constitution, art, and church policy; in the back of the volume, obituaries on Leonard Bacon, 1850-1882 (Box 18)
      - Mostly church-related issues, 1845-1880 (Box 19)
      - Mostly articles by L. W. Bacon and reviews of his writings, 1875-1900 (Box 20)
- 1970 August addition, 1819-1933; Part II
  Part II of the Bacon Family Papers consists of the correspondence, book and sermon manuscripts, newspaper clippings, printed matter, and photos of four generations of the Bacon family, 1819-1933, most notably Leonard Bacon, 1802-1881, Leonard Woolsey Bacon, Sr., 1830-1907, and Leonard Woolsey Bacon, Jr., 1865-1939. The bulk of the collection consists of the manuscript sermons of Leonard Bacon, the historical and theological writings of Leonard Woolsey Bacon, Sr. and Theodore Davenport Bacon, Jr. In addition, there are newspaper clippings and printed articles, lectures, and sermons by several members of the family pertaining to history, religion, congregational polity, and medicine, as well as reform movements, such as, temperance and abolition. Much of the correspondence is personal and pertains to family affairs, but a considerable amount is also devoted to public and professional matters. Of special interest is the Leonard Bacon—Henry Ward Beecher correspondence, 1852-1876, most of which pertains to the Beecher-Tilden controversy. Bacon played a prominent part in this episode serving as moderator for a council of churches called by Beecher's enemies in 1874, and again for a council held in Plymouth Church in 1876. In addition, there is an interesting and important correspondence between Leonard Bacon, a leading champion of temperance, and his brother, David Francis Bacon, who was an alcoholic, that sheds much light on the prevailing attitude toward the problem of alcoholism.
  Music manuscripts and printed materials have been sent to the Music Library.
  Part II is arranged in four series: Series I. Correspondence; Series II. Subject file; Series III. Pinted matter; Series IV. Manuscripts.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Materials in Part II, with the exception of some materials in boxes 1, 2, and 7, are available on microfilm (HM 65). Patrons must consult microfilm instead of originals.
  - Correspondence, Series I
    - Bacon, Alice Mabel, 1909, undated (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Benjamin Wisner, 1893-1915 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, David Francis (brother of Leonard Bacon), 1833-1866 (Box 1)
      Existence and Location of Copies
      Part II, with the exception of some materials in boxes 1, 2, and 7, is available as HM 65 and from Scholarly Resources, Wilmington, Delaware.. Patrons must consult the microfilm instead of the originals.
      Includes correspondence from members of the family pertaining to David's illness (alcoholism).
    - Bacon, Francis, 1841-1858; 1989 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Leonard, 1819-1881
      - Letters to absent church members, 1840 October-November (Box 1)
      - Beecher, Henry Ward--Bacon, (1852)-1880 July-December (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Sr., 1851-1906 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr
      - 1881-1933 (Box 1)
      - Concerning "Energetics", Bacon to Reeve, 1933-1935 (Box 9)
      - Concerning "Energetics", Reeve to Bacon, 1933-1935 (Box 9)
    - Bacon, Lucy (Johnson), 1853 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Nathaniel Terry, 1843-1908 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Seldon, 1893-1904 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Susan A., 1843 (Box 1)
    - Bacon, Theodore Davenport, 1893-1923 (Box 1)
    - Unidentified, 1878-1909 (Box 1)
  - Manuscripts, Series II
    - Bacon, Francis
      - Bacon, Francis?: disease (miscellaneous manuscripts on), Undated (Box 8)
      - The Variability of Diseases, Undated (Box 8)
      - Yellow Fever Experience, Undated (Box 8)
    - Bacon, Leonard
      Items followed by an asterisk (*) were not included in the microfilm publication of the Sermons of Leonard Bacon.
      - Article: annotated typescript of article on David Bacon by Leonard Bacon (*), Undated (Box 1)
      - Article (?): Brooklyn Council of 1876 (rough draft) (*), Undated (Box 1)
      - Book: pertaining to the missionary work of David Bacon among the Indians (*), Undated (Box 1)
      - Book: The Puritan Exodus, chapters 1, 2, 3, and part of 4 (fragment) (*), Undated (Box 1)
      - Discourse (historical), 1858 June (Box 1)
      - Discourse (historical) at Worcester, 1863 September 22 (Box 1)
      - Leonard Bacon?: discourses (special), 1869 (Box 1, Reel 17U)
      - Hymn written by Leonard Bacon (*), 1838 (Box 1)
      - Lectures on dogmatic theology
        - Outline, 1858 (Box 1, Reel 14U)
        - Introduction-XV, 1858 (Box 1, Reel 14U)
        - XV-XXXVII, Undated (Box 1, Reel 14U)
        - XXXVIII-LIV, Undated (Box 1, Reel 14U)
        - LV, Undated (Box 1, Reel 15U)
        - LVI-end, Undated (Box 1, Reel 15U)
      - Lecture notes (Andover) (*), 1820-1823 (Box 2)
      - Lectures (4) on English history, Oliver Cromwell, Wentworth, Land, Charles I, 1844 (Box 2, Reel 9U)
      - Lectures, history and religion, Undated (Box 2, Reel 17U)
      - Memorials (2) of Henry White, Undated (Box 2)
      - Notes, "Can we have a Religious Newspaper for Connecticut" (*), 1875 (Box 2)
      - Notes, historical (*), Undated (Box 2)
      - Notes, for sermons, poems, biographical sketches (*), 1818-1822 (Box 2)
      - Plan for union of Hartford and Yale (*), 1872 (Box 2)
      - Poems and notes (*), Undated (Box 2)
      - Seminary sermons, numbers 1-7, 1823 January 1-1824 December 5 (Box 2, Reel 1U)
      - Sermons
        - 1825 March 13-December 25 (Box 2, Reel 1U)
        - Numbers 59-68, 1826 January 1-March 19 (Box 2, Reel 2U)
        - Numbers 69-78, 1826 March 24-June 11 (Box 2, Reel 2U)
        - 1826 June 18-1827 July 29 (Box 2, Reel 2U)
        - 1827 September 4-1828 September 28 (Box 2, Reel 3U)
        - 1828 October 5-1829 June 28 (Box 3, Reel 3U)
        - 1829 July 10-1830 December 19 (Box 3, Reel 4U)
        - 1831 January 3-1833 December 29 (Box 3, Reel 5U)
        - 1834 January 5-1835 December 27 (Box 3, Reel 6U)
        - 1836 January 13-1837 December 18 (Box 4, Reel 6U)
        - 1837 January 1-1840 December 6 (Box 4, Reel 7U)
        - 1841 January 3-1844 December 8 (Box 4, Reel 8U)
        - 1845 January 5-1847 November 21 (Box 4, Reel 9U)
        - 1848 January 8-1849 December 30 (Box 5, Reel 10U)
        - 1850 January 13-1853 December 25 (Box 5, Reel 11U)
        - 1854 January 8-1855 December 30 (Box 5, Reel 12U)
        - 1856 January 13-1857 May 24 (Box 5, Reel 13U)
        - 1857 July 5-December 6 (Box 6, Reel 13U)
        - 1858 January 3-December 26 (Box 6, Reel 14U)
        - 1859 January 9-1861 December 22 (Box 6, Reel 15U)
        - 1862 January 12-1864 December 4 (Box 6, Reel 16U)
        - 33 Sermons on Mark, 1864 May 15-1865 June 11 (Box 6, Reel 16U)
        - 1866 (Box 6, Reel 16U)
        - 1870-1879 (Box 6, Reel 17U)
        - 1881 (Box 6, Reel 17U)
        - Undated (Box 6, Reel 17U)
      - Speech, autograph copy and newspaper account, 1880 January 29 (Box 6, Reel 17U)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Sr.
      - Biography of Leonard Bacon, Chapters 1-24, Undated (Box 7)
      - Character Studies: H. Bushnell, J. Bunyan, 1889-1891 (Box 7)
      - Character Studies: Mozart, Marcus Whitman, 1891-1897 (Box 7)
      - "Historic Phases of Christian Life and Thought", 1891-1892 (Box 7)
      - "The Sacred Bard before Homer" and related letter, 1898 (Box 7)
      - Sermons at Jacksonville, 1889-1901 (Box 7)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr.
      - "Assignment of Operations", Undated (Box 7)
      - Chapter by chapter notes for a book on surgery, Undated (Box 7)
      - Commemorative Address on Dr. William Beaumont, 1926 June 29 (Box 7)
      - "Data on Poisseule's Experiment", Undated (Box 7)
      - "Diagnosis and Treatment of Perforation in Typhoid", Undated (Box 7)
      - "An Elementary Treatise on Operative Surgery" contents, chapter 2, chapter 3, Undated (Box 7)
      - Fractures, part 1, chapters 1-9, Undated (Box 7)
      - Fractures, part 2, chapters 1-4, Undated (Box 7)
      - Hinged Plaster of Paris Splints
        - Chapter 1, Undated (Box 7)
        - Chapter 1 (fragment), Undated (Box 7)
        - Chapter 2, parts A, B, Undated (Box 7)
        - Chapter 2, parts C, D, E, Undated (Box 7)
        - Chapter 2, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 2 and some revisions, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 2, early draft, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 2, table of computed values, Undated (Box 8)
        - Tentative computations and explanations, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 3, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 3, rejected portion of draft, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 4, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 5, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 5, fragment, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter 5, photographs, Undated (Box 8)
        - Photographs, notes, drawings for manuscript, Undated (Box 8)
      - Julian the Apostate (2 essays), Undated (Box 8)
      - Mimeographed correspondence with Francis Bacon concerning the New Haven Medical Association, 1897 (Box 8)
      - A New Method of Amputation at the Knee, Undated (Box 8)
      - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr?: Lectures on Surgical Tuberculosis, first half, Undated (Box 8)
      - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr?: Lectures on Surgical Tuberculosis, second half, Undated (Box 8)
      - Letter of Criticism, Bacon to Charles Sajous, 1910 (Box 8)
      - The Theory and Practice of the Treatment of Tetanus, Undated (Box 8)
      - An Analytic Critique of "The Cost of Competition" by S. A. Reeve, 1906 (Box 9)
      - A Discursive Discussion of Motion, Undated (Box 9)
      - Energetics
        - Book 1, prefaces and contents, Undated (Box 9)
        - Book 1-6, Undated (Box 9)
        - Appendices, Undated (Box 9)
        - Reeve's draft of manuscript, Undated (Box 9)
        - Essay on water running uphill, Undated (Box 9)
        - Comments, suggestions and emendations of the manuscript, Undated (Box 9)
        - Discarded chapters, Undated (Box 9)
      - (Energetics?), notes, miscellaneous calculations, drawings, and rough drafts, Undated (Box 9)
      - The Mechanism of Blood Propulsion
        - Pages 1-289, Undated (Box 9)
        - Notes and drafts, Undated (Box 10)
        - Notes, Undated (Box 10)
        - Contents and other notes, Undated (Box 10)
        - Notes, items pertaining to chapters 1-23, Undated (Box 10)
      - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr.? (in his handwriting), sermon, "Be not righteous overmuch", Ecclesiastes 7:25, Undated (Box 10)
      - Translation copy of "A Compendious Compass for Drawing Ellipses, Parabolas and Hyperbolas" by Richard Meyh, Undated (Box 10)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey III
      - "Qualitative Surveys of Current Situations" with emendations by his father Leonard Woolsey Bacon Jr. and their coorespondence about the manuscript, Undated (Box 10)
        For additional manuscript material see Box 11
    - (Bacon, Theodore?)
      - Chapter 4, Elijah and Elisha, Undated (Box 11)
      - "Medical Practice in N.H. Colony 1650-1693", Undated (Box 11)
      - "Hooke's Sermon", 1641 (Box 11)
      - "Davenport on Church Government", 1672 (Box 11)
      - "Memorial of First Church of Boston", Undated (Box 11)
      - "Pageant: David Bacon and His Work", Undated (Box 11)
    - Bacon, Theodore D.
      - Book Reviews: Ignatius Loyola; Benjamin Franklin; My Idea of God; Unitarian Faith; Erasmus, Undated (Box 8)
      - Biography of Leonard Bacon
        - Chapter VI, rise of colonization, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter VII, downfall of colonization, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter VIII, book on slavery, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter XI, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter XIV, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter XV, academic years/post Civil War, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter XVI, the Beecher troubles, Undated (Box 8)
        - Chapter XVII, Undated (Box 8)
      - "In Quest of the Last Radiance of the Christian Religion", Undated (Box 10)
      - Jesus and Prohibition, Undated (Box 11)
      - Jesus' Use of the Word 'Heaven', Undated (Box 11)
      - Miscellaneous short religious manuscripts (possible for Sunday School use), Undated (Box 11)
      - Notes on the Life of Leonard Bacon, for biography of the same, Undated (Box 11)
      - Notes on Leonard Bacon
        - Chronology and notes on the Beecher trouble, Undated (Box 11)
        - Notes on Tribune, Times, Beecher, Undated (Box 11)
        - Abstracts of Leonard Bacon's articles, Independent, 1871-1881 (Box 11)
        - Xn. Un., 1870-1871 (Box 11)
      - Paul (Biblical), mimeo copies of first lesson, The Gift of the Spirit, Undated (Box 11)
      - Paul (Biblical), miscellaneous lessons, and also Sunday School tests on the material, Undated (Box 11)
      - The Popular Appeal of Primitive Christianity, Undated (Box 11)
      - Sermons (list), and also manuscripts, Paul and the Early Church; Introduction to Beginnings; Introduction to Story of Israel, Undated (Box 11)
  - Printed matter, Series III
    - Bacon, Francis
      - Newspaper clippings: funeral and bequest, 1912 (Box 10)
      - Medical pamphlets, 1870-1906 (Box 12)
      - Wife's charity reports, 1892 (Box 12)
    - Bacon, Leonard
      - Newspaper clipping, 1850 December 21 (Box 10)
      - Letter on fugitive slave law, 1852 April 21 (Box 10)
      - Newspaper clippings: pertaining to "higher law", 1850-1852 (Box 10)
      - Newspaper articles, 1880 (Box 10)
      - (Bacon, Leonard) Miscellaneous news clippings, Undated (Box 10)
      - Address; preface; remarks; paper, 1829-1869 (Box 12)
      - Addresses, 1838-1869 (Box 12)
      - "An Appeal Against Division", 1840 (Box 12)
      - Catalogues of persons admitted to the First Church in New Haven, 3 volumes cover years 1685-1583, 1854 (Box 12)
      - Assorted discourses, 1840-1866 (Box 12)
      - Hymn, letter, reply to letter, recollection, 1838-1881(?) (Box 12)
      - Seven letters to G. A. Calhoun, 1840 (Box 13)
      - Manuals of the First Church in New Haven, 1860-1877 (Box 13)
      - Memorial, articles, orations, 1858-1882 (Box 13)
      - Sermons, 1825-1879 (Box 13)
      - Sermons, reprinted in "The National Preacher", 1828-1852 (Box 13)
      - Volume: historical discourse delivered at Worcester in Old South Meeting House, 1863 (Box 13)
      - Volume (memorial) about Bacon, 1882 (Box 13)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Sr.
      - News clippings
        - 250th anniversary of Congregational Church, 1901 (Box 10)
        - Pertaining to the Congregational Church, 1901 (Box 10)
        - Pertaining to the Congregational Church, 1905 (Box 10)
        - Obituary notice, 1907 (Box 10)
      - Church and religious pamphlets, 1868-1899 (Box 13)
      - Church, religious and historical pamphlets, 1900-1906 (Box 13)
      - Memorial discourses, 1882-1926 (Box 13)
      - Memorial for Susan Bacon, 1887 (Box 13)
      - Poetry, 1906-1920 (Box 13)
      - Sermons, 1871-1905 (Box 13)
      - Volume: "Irenics and Polemics", Undated (Box 13)
    - Bacon, Theodore
      - News clippings: obituary notices, 1900 (Box 10)
      - Political and legal pamphlets, 1876-1897 (Box 14)
    - Bacon family
      - News clipping: Riot (Yale), Undated (Box 10)
      - News clipping: 125th anniversary of Talmadge Church, 1934 (Box 10)
      - Bacon Family, postcard scrapbooks, Undated (Box 10)
    - (Smith, Russel?), art book with some handwritten manuscripts, Undated (Box 10)
    - Bacon, Alice Mabel, story in "The Barnard Bear", 1908 (Box 12)
    - Bacon, B.W., of Yale, "Pharisees and Herodians", 1920 (Box 12)
    - Bacon, David
      - "Pastor's Greeting" (memorial about David Bacon), 1892 (Box 12)
      - "Pastor's Greeting" (memorial), 1892 (Box 12)
      - Memorial pageant service, 1894 (Box 12)
    - Bacon, David Francis, "The Student's Companion", 1831 (Box 12)
    - Bacon, Delia, volume, 1939 (Box 12)
    - Bacon, Edward Woolsey, memorial concerning him, 1888 (Box 12)
    - Bacon, George B.
      - "Farewell Letter", 1876 (Box 12)
      - "Tennyson and Idyls", 1860 (Box 12)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr.
      - Medical pamphlets, 1899-1923 (Box 13)
      - Printed materials concerning his works as a Yale student, 1886 (Box 13)
    - Bacon, Nathaniel T., pamphlets on American debt and expansion, Russia and physics, 1900-1919 (Box 14)
    - Bacon, Theodore D., religious pamphlets, 1907-1923 (Box 14)
    - Bacon, Selden, "On the 10th Amendment", 1930 (Box 14)
    - Professor Bacon of Berkeley, California Medical Bulletin, 1906 (Box 14)
    - Bacon Collection of miscellaneous pamphlets
      - Church programs, Undated (Box 14)
      - Church and religious pamphlets, Undated (Box 14)
      - Connecticut and Yale pamphlets, 1839-1888 (Box 14)
      - Journals: "The Independent" and "Hebroica", Undated (Box 14)
      - Medical, 1854-1895 (Box 14)
      - Admission of California, 1848-1850 (Box 14)
      - "Higher Law" and "Fugitive Slave Law", 1851-1852 (Box 14)
      - Religious and reminiscences, Undated (Box 14)
      - Political, historical, and miscellaneous pamphlets, 1860-1903 (Box 14)
      - Political pamphlets, 1854-1863 (Box 14)
      - Proceedings of Connecticut Medical Society, 1818-1842 (Box 14)
      - School folders (catalogue) and bulletin on termite control, Undated (Box 14)
      - Sermons, 1724, 1773 (Box 14)
      - Sermons, 1920, 1923 (Box 14)
      - Memoir and memorial address, Undated (Box 14)
      - "Yahveh Christ" by MacWhorter, Undated (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous volume: Gefangbildundslebre, Undated (Box 14)
    - Bacon, N. A., financial ledger, 1864 (Box 15)
  - Subject file, Series IV
    - Bacon Family collection
      - Photograph, Undated (Box 10)
      - Photograph, engraving, and silhouette, Undated (Box 10)
      - Photographs, miscellaneous, Undated (Box 10)
    - Bacon, Alice, obituary (memorial essay), 1850 (Box 11)
    - Bacon, Mrs. Francis, state board of charities, 1892-1893 (Box 11)
    - Bacon, Leonard
      - Books purchased for Mr. Evarts, 1822 (Box 11)
      - Correspondence and newspaper article on women's suffrage, Undated (Box 11)
      - Personal finances, bills, Undated (Box 11)
      - Speeches and proceeding of anti-Nebraska meeting, 1859 (Box 11)
      - Will, Undated (Box 11)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Sr., music: Ten Canticles and Cantata, Undated (Box 11)
    - Bacon, Leonard Woolsey, Jr.
      - Bankbook, Undated (Box 11)
      - Certificate to practice medicine, 1893 (Box 11)
      - Composition book, Undated (Box 11)